Guide to the ILGWU. Sol Chaikin papers,
ILGWU. Sol Chaikin papers,
- Series X. Speeches
  - Speech on U.S. Foreign Policy [Folder 1 of 3], 1978 (Box 47, Folder 49)
    given to the Trilateral Commission, June 11
  - Speech on U.S. Foreign Policy [Folder 2 of 2], 1978 (Box 47, Folder 50)
  - Speech on U.S. Foreign Policy [Folder 3 of 3], 1978 (Box 47, Folder 51)
  - Speech on Unemployment and Inflation [Folder 1 of 3], 1978 (Box 47, Folder 52)
    given at the Columbia University Arden House, June 15
  - Speech on Unemployment and Inflation [Folder 2 of 3], 1978 (Box 47, Folder 53)
    Given at the Columbia University Arden House, June 15
  - Speech on Unemployment and Inflation [Folder 3 of 3], 1978 (Box 47, Folder 54)
  - Questions and Answers from the Arden House Speech on Unemployment and Inflation [Folder 1 of 3], 1978 (Box 47, Folder 55)
    June 15
  - Questions and Answers from the Arden House Speech on Unemployment and Inflation [Folder 2 of 3], 1978 (Box 47, Folder 56)
  - Questions and Answers from the Arden House Speech on Unemployment and Inflation [Folder 3 of 3], 1978 (Box 47, Folder 57)
  - Questions and Answers from the Arden House Speech on Unemployment and Inflation, 1978 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Speech Comparing U.S. and Israeli Trade Union Practices and Theory, 1978 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    given to the Histadrut Executive Council, June 25
  - AFL-CIO Commitment To Histadrut. A Historic View, 1978 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    July 15
  - The Impact Of Exports On The American Economy. Agenda For America, 1978 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    From USA Today, July 17; given at the ACTWU Convention, September 22
  - Handwritten Address on the Similarities Between the U.S. and German Trade Union Movements. History of the ILG and the Garment Industry, 1978 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    given at the 13th Congress of the German Textile and Clothing Workers Union, October 2; given at the 1978 Seminar Kannenberg Amphi, Fashion Institute of Technology, October 23
  - History of the ILG and the Garment Industry. Reports written by Florida Institute of Technology Students on Chaikin's Speech on the History of the ILGWU, 1978 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    given at the 1978 Seminar Kannennberg Amphi, Fashion Institute of Technology, October 23; given at FIT
  - Interview with the Swedish Broadcasting Corporation. Is There A Future For The Garment Industry In New York?, 1978 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    October 26; given at the Midtown realty Owner's Luncheon, November 2
  - Organized Labor. Its Historic Role and Future Mission, 1978 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    Given at the Wilheln Weinberg Seminar, November 13
  - The Impact of Imports on the American Economy, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    From USA Today, January
  - Free Trade or Fair Trade for America [Folder 1 of 2], 1979 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    given at Vassar College, February 5
  - Free Trade or Fair Trade for America [Folder 2 of 2], 1979 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Interview with Archie Robinson for an Oral History and a Book on George Meany, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    February 25
  - Toward the 1980s. The Need for New Approaches. American Business in Mexico, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    given at the Social Democrats Eugene V. Debs Award, March 7; from the MacNeil-Lehrer Report, March 12
  - Collective Bargaining Issues for the 1980s. Work in America. The Decade Ahead, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 14)
    March 14
  - Negotiations [Folder 1 of 2], 1979 (Box 48, Folder 15)
    given to the Opening Session, Outerwear Division, March 21
  - Negotiations [Folder 2 of 2], 1979 (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Likenesses Between Great Britain and the U.S. In Attitude, Problems, and Outlook, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 17)
    given at the General Conference of the national Union of Tailors and Garment Worker, April 23
  - Likenesses Between Great Britain and the U.S. In Attitude, Problems, and Outlook. The Tokyo Round and Beyond, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 18)
    given at the General Conference of the National Union of Tailors and Garment Workers, April 23; given to the Committee for Economic Development, May 17
  - The Tokyo Round and Beyond. Corporate Responsibility, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 19)
    Given to the Committee for Economic Development, May 17; given at the AACSB Meeting, May 24
  - Arden House. Collective Bargaining Issues and the Structure of the American Labor Movement Today [Folder 1 of 2], 1979 (Box 48, Folder 20)
    June 6
  - Arden House. Collective Bargaining Issues and the Structure of the American Labor Movement Today [Folder 2 of 2], 1979 (Box 48, Folder 21)
  - Statement Made Before the Senate Committee on Finance on the Threat of Imports. Interview on the Steve Powers Program [Radio] Concerning the Oil Crisis, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 22)
    August 8
  - Needed Improvements in Unemployment Compensation. A Statement made by Chaikin on Behalf of the ILGWU Before the National Commission on Unemployment Compensation. Labor and the ILGWU, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 23)
    August 24; given at the NY Sportswear Joint Board Seminar at Unity House, September 4
  - Labor and the ILGWU. Speech Given at the "To The Friends of Carter-Mondale Dinner", 1979 (Box 48, Folder 24)
    given at the NY Sportswear Joint Board Seminar at Unity House, September 4; on why the ILGWU Supports Carter, October 24
  - Speech Given at the "To the Friends of Carter-Mondale Dinner". American Education in the Eighties, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 25)
    on why the ILGWU Supports Carter, October 24; given to the American Council on Education, November 1
  - American Education in the Eighties, 1979 (Box 48, Folder 26)
    given to the American Council on Education, November 1
  - Speech on the Importance of the ILGWU's Past Which Highlights Certain Achievements. The Effects of Recent Trade Developments on Unemployment. A Larger Perspective [Folder 1 of 2], 1980 (Box 48, Folder 27)
    Given at the Opening of the ILGWU archives, January 24; given to the Canadian Group Trilateral Commission, January 31
  - Speech on the Importance of the ILGWU's Past Which Highlights Certain Achievements. The Effects of Recent Trade Developments on Unemployment. A Larger Perspective [Folder 2 of 2], 1980 (Box 48, Folder 28)
    Given at the opening of the ILGWU archives, January 24; given to the Canadian Group Trilateral commission, January 31
  - Presidential Classroom for Young Americans [Folder 1 of 2], 1980 (Box 48, Folder 29)
    February 8
  - Presidential Classroom for Young Americans [Folder 2 of 2], 1980 (Box 48, Folder 30)
  - Middle East Intervention, 1980 (Box 48, Folder 31)
    given to the Trilateral commission, March 25
  - Collective Bargaining Speech, 1980 (Box 48, Folder 32)
    Made at the Automation House, April 30
  - Collective Bargaining Speech. Labor in Socialist Societies. Blue Collar Workers in Eastern Europe, 1980 (Box 48, Folder 33)
    made at the Automation House, April 30; given at Stanford University, May 14
  - Employment in the Textile and Clothing Industries. An Industrialized Country View [Folder 1 of 2], 1980 (Box 48, Folder 34)
    given at the Symposium on International trade in Textiles and Clothing under the Multi-fibre Arrangement, May 28
  - Employment in the Textile and Clothing Industries. An Industrialized Country View [Folder 2 of 2], 1980 (Box 48, Folder 35)
    given at the Symposium on International Trade in Textiles and Clothing under the Multi-fibre Arrangement, May 28
  - Speech Given at the Training Institute on the Ideals of the ILGWU, 1980 (Box 48, Folder 36)
    June 5
  - Labor's Critical Issue. The Two-Tiered Society [Folder 1 of 2], 1980 (Box 48, Folder 37)
    Submitted for publication to the Journal of Socioeconomic Studies, July 8
  - Labor's Critical Issue. The Two-Tiered Society [Folder 2 of 2], 1980 (Box 48, Folder 38)
    submitted for publication to the Journal of Socioeconomic Studies, July 8
  - To the American Academy of Family Physicians Concerning a Health Education Program. Sol C. Chaikin Seconding the Nomination of Jimmy Carter. Social and Governmental Costs of Lifting Import Restrictions. A Letter to the Editor of the New York Times, 1980 (Box 48, Folder 39)
    August 1; August 13; August 24
  - Address to the Convention of the International Union of Electrical Workers. To The WWD with Corrections. For Print in the Springfield Republican Concerning Productivity. Speech on the Problems with the Multifiber Textiles Agreement, 1980 (Box 48, Folder 40)
    September 16; for their article concerning the ILGWU and J.P. Stevens, September 26; October 3; given to the Congress on the International Textile Garment and Leather Worker's Federation, October 8
  - Speech on the Problems with the Multifiber Textiles Agreement [Imports]. General Outline of the Address of Mr. P. Wurth, 1980 (Box 48, Folder 41)
    given to the congress of ILGWU Federation, October 8; Chairman, Textiles Surveillance Body, Geneva, on the background of the Multifibers Textiles Agreement at the Congress of the ILGWU Federation, October 8
  - Speech Economic Stagnation and Price Inflation. Lower Minimum Wage for Teens?, 1980 (Box 48, Folder 42)
    given at the Joint Economic Committee, Economic Policy Conference, December 10; Interview in U.S. News and World Report, December 15
  - Speech Concerning Defeat of Carter in 1980 Election. Statement of Dissent Concerning the Commission on U.S. Brazilian Relations (Box 48, Folder 43)
    November 12; Recommendation that the United States Continue a unilateral policy of liberal trade regulations vis-à-vis Brazil, November 13
  - Labor's Critical Issue. The Two-Tiered Society from the Journal of the Institute for Socioeconomic Studies. Proposed Forward to Professor Barnard Karsh's Book Diary of a Strike, 1980 (Box 48, Folder 44)
    December 17; University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, December 17
  - Statement by Morty Bahr Supporting the Nomination of Sandy Frucher as State Industrial Commissioner (Box 48, Folder 45)
    Speech seemingly given to professors or university presidents concerning unions
  - Metropolitan America. Business and Work (Box 48, Folder 46)
    a radio or TV show
  - Speech Given to the Jewish Labor Committee on the Helsinki Final Act [Folder 1 of 2], 1981 (Box 48, Folder 47)
    January 19
  - Speech Given to the Jewish Labor Committee on the Helsinki Final Act [Folder 2 of 2], 1981 (Box 48, Folder 48)
  - Fallacies of Lower-Than-Minimum Wages for Youth. Testimony at Leichter Hearings on Sweatshops, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 49)
    from the Washington Star, February 11; March 4
  - Testimony at Leichter Hearings on Sweatshops, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 50)
    March 4
  - Undocumented Workers. Statement for the 75th Anniversary Observance of the American Jewish Committee, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 51)
    Article submitted for the Brandeis Quarterly, March 25; April 1
  - Speech on Social and Economic Justice. Speech on Economic Revitalization, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 52)
    given at the Mr. C. Zimmerman Luncheon, April 4; given at Columbia University, April 25
  - Speech on Economic Revitalization, 1981 (Box 48, Folder 53)
    given at Columbia University, April 25
  - Testimony Before the Labor Standards Subcommittee Hearings of Industrial Homework. Statement of the AFL-CIO Social Security Committee. Speech Criticizing the Reagan Administration, 1981 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    May 19; Headed by Chaikin on Human Resources House Select Committee on Aging on the Administration's Social Security Proposals, June 1; given at the ACTWU Convention, June 3
  - Speech Criticizing the Reagan Administration, 1981 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    given at the ACTWU Convention, June 3
  - Getting to Know, 1981 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    June 10
  - Getting to Know. Article on International Trade to Appear in the Book Toward a New U.S. Industrial Policy, 1981 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    June 10; June 29
  - Statement of the ILGWU in Opposition to the Removal of Restrictions on Industrial Homework, 1981 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    July 1
  - Statement of the ILGWU in Opposition to the Removal of Restrictions on Industrial Homework. DNC Article on Supply-Side Economics, 1981 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    July 1; July9
  - WEVD Radio Interview of Phil Comstock by Dorothy Thomas. Address Concerning the Election of Reagan. Organized Labor's All-American Role. Past and Present, 1981 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    September 2; given to the British Trades Union Congress, September 7; a letter to the editor of the NY Times, October 2
  - Statement of the ILGWU on Amnesty for Undocumented Workers Submitted to the United States Sub-Committee on Immigration and Refugee Policy, 1981 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    October 29
  - Speech on Imports [Folder 1 of 2], 1981 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    given at the Symposium on International trade and the American Economy, November 30
  - Speech on Imports [Folder 2 of 2], 1981 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    given at the symposium on international trade and the American economy, November 30
  - Speech on Imports. Joint Statement by Labor Leaders Denouncing the Liberal Party's Endorsement of John Anderson (Box 49, Folder 11)
    given at the 1981 Centennial Convention of the ILGWU
  - Speech to the City Club of New York, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    on sweatshops, March 5
  - Speech to The City Club of New York. Where Do We Go From Here?, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 13)
    on sweatshops, March 5; given to the American for Democratic Action, March 6
  - Where Do We Go From Here?, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    Given to the Americans for Democratic Action, March 6
  - Interview by Ralph Howard on WMCA Radio. Foreign Affair, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 15)
    April 20
  - Summary of Chaikin's Statement Before the Subcommittee on Savings, Pensions, and Investment Policy of the Senate Committee on Finance. The Enterprise Zone Act of 1982 [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 49, Folder 16)
    on S. 2298; April 21
  - Summary of Chaikin's Statement Before the Subcommittee on Savings, Pensions, and Investment Policy of the Senate Committee on Finance. The Enterprise Zone Act of 1982 [Folder 2 of 2] (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - Enterprise Zones. Reagan's Mythical Job Creation from the AFL-CIO News' Labor News Conference Mutual Broadcasting System. Labor The Working Poor and America's Two- Tiered Economy, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 18)
    April 28;May 7
  - Labor, The Working Poor and America's Two-Tiered Economy, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 19)
    May 7
  - Labor Views of Government [Folder 1 of 3], 1982 (Box 49, Folder 20)
    given at the Arden House, Columbia University, July 17
  - Labor Views of Government [Folder 2 of 3], 1982 (Box 49, Folder 21)
    given at the Arden House, Columbia university, July 17
  - Labor Views of Government [Folder 3 of 3], 1982 (Box 49, Folder 22)
  - Speech on Imports [Folder 1 of 2], 1982 (Box 49, Folder 23)
    given at Northeastern University, June 18
  - Speech on Imports [Folder 2 of 2], 1982 (Box 49, Folder 24)
  - Statement Before the U.S. Senate Committee on Finance on S. 2237. Letter in Reply to Anti-Union Letter which Appeared in the New York Times. Speech on the Activities of the ILGWU in the U.S., 1981-1982 (Box 49, Folder 25)
    The Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act, August 10; Submitted to the New York Times; Op. Ed. Page for publication, October 2; given at the ILGWU Conference in Quebec, October 10-11
  - A Discussion Concerning South African Unions [Folder 1 of 2], 1982 (Box 49, Folder 26)
    given to Yale University's Southern African Research Program, December 3
  - A Discussion Concerning South African Unions [Folder 2 of 2], 1982 (Box 49, Folder 27)
    given at Yale University's Southern African Research Program, December 3
  - Let's Find Out. A WCBS Radio Program [Folder 1 of 2], 1982 (Box 49, Folder 28)
    December 26
  - Let's Find Out. A WCBS Radio Program [Folder 2 of 2], 1982 (Box 49, Folder 29)
  - Statement Regarding the Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1982. Coping with Youth Unemployment, The Dimensions of the Problem (Box 49, Folder 30)
  - Trade, Investment and Deindustrialization. Myth and Reality, 1982 (Box 49, Folder 31)
    from Foreign Affairs, Spring
  - Toward a Rational Immigration Policy. Trade, Investment and Deindustrialization. Myth and Reality (Box 49, Folder 32)
    from the Journal, The Social Institute of Socioeconomic Studies; From Portfolio: International Economic Perspectives
  - Report of an AFL-CIO Delegation to South Africa. Statement Before the U.S. House of Representatives' Committee of Ways and Means' Subcommittee on Trade, 1983 (Box 49, Folder 33)
    February 10; on FY 1984 Budget Proposals, February 18
  - Speech About the Problems the Union Must Face, 1983 (Box 49, Folder 34)
    Given at the Joint Council Meeting, March 10
  - Statement Before the U.S. House of Representatives' Committee on Ways and Means' Subcommittee on Trade, 1983 (Box 49, Folder 35)
    for hearings on trade remedy laws, March 16
  - Statement before the U.S. House of Representatives' Committee on Ways and Means' Subcommittee on Trade. On Antidumping and Counterveiling Duty Laws. Statement before the Senate Committee on Finance Regarding S. 98 and S. 863 entitled Enterprise Zone Emp, 1983 (Box 49, Folder 36)
    March 16; May 3; May 10
  - Toward a Rational Development Policy [Folder 1 of 2], 1983 (Box 49, Folder 37)
    given at the 30th Anniversary International Development Conference, May 17
  - Toward a Rational Development Policy [Folder 2 of 2], 1983 (Box 49, Folder 38)
  - Notecards for Speech on Economic Revitalization, 1983 (Box 49, Folder 39)
    given at Columbia University's Graduate School of Business, June
  - Copies of Notecards for Speech on Economic Revitalization. Speech on the Importance of Affordable Housing. Statement on Deindustrialization, 1983 (Box 49, Folder 40)
    given at Columbia University's Graduate School of Business, June; given for the ILGWU Cooperative House's 21st Birthday Message, June; June
  - Statement Before the International Trade Commission in the Matter of Investigation No. 332-154 U.S. Trade Related Employment [Folder 1 of 3], 1983 (Box 49, Folder 41)
    June 30
  - Statement Before the International Trade Commission in the Matter of Investigation No. 332-154 U.S. Trade Related Employment [Folder 2 of 3], 1983 (Box 49, Folder 42)
  - Statement Before the International Trade Commission in the Matter of Investigation No. 332-154 U.S. Trade Related Employment [Folder 3 of 3], 1983 (Box 49, Folder 43)
  - Index cards for Speech on Imports Before the Senate's Committee on Banking and Finance. Letter on Imports to the Editor of Barron's Weekly. Coalition Letter In Support Of Jobs Bill. Closing Of Brooklyn Wage And Hour Office Will Cripple Drive Against Sweatshops, an ILGWU press release, 1983 (Box 49, Folder 44)
    July 30; August 15; September 12; An ILGWU Press Release, October 13
  - Public Elementary and High Schools. Yesterday and Today. Statement on the Re-Establishment of Townsend Harris High, 1983 (Box 49, Folder 45)
    given at Adelphi University's 1983 Robert Finkelstein Memorial Lecture, October 26; December 20
  - Coping with Youth Unemployment. The Dimensions of the Problem [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 49, Folder 46)
  - Coping with Youth Unemployment. The Dimensions of the Problem [Folder 2 of 2] (Box 49, Folder 47)
  - Notecards for Speech on Imports (Box 49, Folder 48)
  - The Needs of the Labor-Intensive Sector [Chapter 18]. Statement of Sol C. Chaikin Regarding the Decision of the U.S. Supreme Court in INS vs. Delgado. Two Untitled Items (Box 49, Folder 49)
    one about social security, the other about economics
  - Labor Looks at Health Care. Managing Health Care in the Workplace [Folder 1 of 2], 1984 (Box 49, Folder 50)
    given at the Conference Board, January 26
  - Labor Looks at Health Care. Managing Health Care in the Workplace [Folder 2 of 2], 1984 (Box 49, Folder 51)
  - Outline of Major Points of Speech on Imports and Labor Sensitive Industries. Testimony Before The Subcommittee On Economic Stabilization Of The House Committee On Banking, Finance, And Urban Affairs. Speech about Imports and Labor Sensitive Industries. A, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 52)
    given before the Subcommittee on Economic Stabilization of the House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs, January 26; January 31
  - Testimony Before The Subcommittee On Economic Stabilization Of The House Committee On Banking, Finance, And Urban Affairs. Statement before the Subcommittee on Labor of the Senate Committee on Labor and Human Resources, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 53)
    on a national industrial policy, January 31; on S. 2145, the Fair Labor Standards Act, February 9
  - Statement before the Subcommittee on Labor of the Senate Committee on Labor and Human Resources, on S. 2145, the Fair Labor Standards Act. Speech on American Economy Reprinted in "Trialogue." ILGWU Press Release Praising Jane Fonda for Insisting her Line, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 54)
    February 9; April; April 5; Given at the 1984 AFL-CIO Civil Rights Conference, April 5
  - Speech on Labor Unions and Civil Rights. Comments on the LICIT Paper, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 55)
    given at the 1984 AFL-CIO Civil Rights Conference, April 5; "International Trade, Industrial Policies and the Future of American Industry", April 6
  - Testimony on the U.S.'s Merchandise Trade Deficit. Statement Submitted to the Subcommittee on Compensation and Employee Benefits, Committee on Post Office and Civil Service, U.S. House of Representatives on H.R. 4599 "The Federal Employees' Pay Equity A, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 56)
    given before the Subcommittee of Trade, Committee on Ways and Means, U.S. House of Representatives, April 12; April 23
  - Testimony on the U.S.'s Merchandise Trade Deficit. Statement Submitted to the Subcommittee on Compensation and Employee Benefits, On H.R. 4599, "The Federal Employees' Pay Equity Act of 1984" (Box 49, Folder 57)
    given before the Subcommittee on trade, Committee on Ways and Means, U.S. House of Representatives, April 12; April 23
  - Statement Submitted to the Subcommittee on Compensation and Employee Benefits. Industrial Union Department Industrial Policy, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 58)
    on H.R. 4599, "The Federal Employees' Pay Equity Act of 1984" April 23; May 11
  - Acceptance Speech for the Gompers/Murray/Meany Award. Industrial Policy and the Labor-Intensive Sector, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 59)
    May 24; text for a chapter of the book The Politics of Industrial Policy by Sharon Zukin, June 13
  - Statement Concerning Tariff Reductions before the Subcommittee on Trade. Labor Day Statement Concerning Imports. Speech in Montreal Concerning the Challenges Union Must Face, 1984 (Box 49, Folder 60)
    June 21; September 3; September 22
  - Testimony Concerning U.S. Trade Policy [Folder 1 of 2], 1984 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    given before the Subcommittee on International Economic Policy, U.S. Senate Committee on Foreign Relations, September 26
  - Testimony Concerning U.S. Trade Policy [Folder 2 of 2], 1984 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Comments on New Labor Department Rules Permitting Industrial Homework in Knitted Outerwear. Poverty, Unemployment, and the Changing American Economy. Statement Regarding the U.S. Bishops' Draft Pastoral Letter, 1984 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    November 16; delivered to the Association for Social Education, December; on Catholic Social Teaching and the U.S. economy, December
  - Some Thoughts on the Future of Work in America. Apparel Imports: A Threat to the Nation. Reunion of Old Timers (Box 50, Folder 4)
    by Evelyn Dubrow and Herman Starobin; given on Gus Tyler's 50th Anniversary with the ILGWU
  - Rebuttal to an Article in Business Week (Box 50, Folder 5)
    by Jane S. Shaw on the Sub-minimum wage
  - Comments of the ILGWU on the U.S. Bishops' Pastoral Letter on the Economy. The Youth Sub-Minimum Wage: Reagan's Patent Medicine, 1985 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    January; March 9